http://www.cawq.ca/en/privacy_policy.html

June 7, 2004
The Canadian Association on Water Quality (CAWQ) is an organization of
scientists, engineers, technologists, administrators and students engaged or
interested in research on water quality or in the control or treatment of water
pollution.
CAWQ is committed to ensuring its members right to privacy. The following
privacy policy will be posted on our website and included in our by-laws.
The CAWQ considers personal information to be any information that can
be used to distinguish, identify or contact a specific individual. In the case
of internal communications, where an individual uses his or her home
contact information as business contact information, the contact
information provided is regarded as business contact information, and is
not subject to protection as personal information (e.g., for purposes of
producing lists of members and the Board of Directors).
The CAWQ will advise individuals of the purpose of any information
collected, what the information will be used for and to whom the
information is going to be disclosed. Information collected will be limited
to that which is necessary for the purposes identified. The CAWQ will not
use this consent for additional purposes that may arise in the future.
However, consent will be presumed when utilizing the information to meet
our obligations as an association; e.g., communicating directly with our
members. Any mechanisms for obtaining consent will be obvious when
the information is to be disclosed, and will be immediately available and
easy to use.
The CAWQ will obtain appropriate consent from individual members.
The CAWQ will strive to maintain personal information accurate, complete
and up-to-date. Upon request, an individual shall be provided with access
to their information. All requests to view information collected by CAWQ
will be referred to the Privacy Officer. Any requests to view personal
information collected through other means must be made in writing to the
CAWQ Secretary. A written response will be provided
within seven (7) business days.
The CAWQ has appointed a Privacy Officer to whom
any questions or concerns regarding compliance with this policy should be
directed. Should an individual's concerns not be addressed satisfactorily,
the complainant should send a letter to the President of the CAWQ, outlining the concerns and steps taken to resolve the
situation to date.
Information collected by CAWQ
The CAWQ maintains a database of its membership and subscribers to the
Water Quality Research Journal of Canada (WQRJC). The membership
database is updated on an annual basis. As a provider of continuing education
sessions through its symposia and as publisher of the WQRJC, CAWQ collects
information from registrants and exhibitors, purchasers of CAWQ publications,
presenters, and individuals seeking information on membership.
All information collected by the CAWQ is stored in a secured location.
The CAWQ does not loan or rent membership contact information.
CAWQ Website
The CAWQ website may automatically record some general information about
visitors, such as type of browser and operating system used, Internet domain for
the Internet service provider, and date and time of visit, web pages visited, along
with the address of the previous website, if linked to www.CAWQ.ca from another website.
This tracking system does not record personal information about individuals or
link this information to any personal data collected.
Use of Internet "Cookies"
CAWQ may use "cookies" that identify return visitors. A cookie is a piece of data
that a website can send to a browser, which may then store the cookie on the
hard drive. This allows return visitors to receive information tailored to their
individual preferences. The purpose is to save time, provide return visitors with a
more meaningful visit and to measure website security.
"Cookies" do not contain any personally identifying information. Web browsers
such as Netscape and Internet Explorer allow users to disable cookie collection,
if desired, or be advised when a cookie is being stored on a hard drive.
Information Collected by Third Parties
The CAWQ may receive or transmit membership information from organizations
including its parent organization (the International Water Association) and those
that have been designated as partner organizations by the Board of the CAWQ.
Membership information will be used in a manner that is in compliance with the
privacy policies of the CAWQ and the partner organization and with current
legislation restricting use of such information. The CAWQ concurs that this
information will only be used for the purpose for which it was provided.
The CAWQ website contains links to other sites, and once users link to another
site, they become subject to the privacy and security policies of the new site.
The CAWQ encourages users to read the privacy policies of all websites they
visit, especially if they choose to share any personal information.
Please note that currently the CAWQ does not utilize encryption software but is
planning to use it in a not too distant future. Therefore, we are currently unable
to ensure that information sent by individuals via e-mail is secure from third
parties.
How CAWQ Utilizes Collected Information
In addition to informing our members about pertinent information in the
sector, CAWQ uses the information it collects for marketing purposes and
statistical purposes, e.g., to advise/remind members and non-members of
selected upcoming events and activities.
Information for statistical analysis - CAWQ may disclose non-personal
information to third parties such as conference sponsors or advertisers
and/or use the information for auditing purposes or increasing the
usefulness of services.
Opting Out
CAWQ recognizes that its members may wish to limit use of personal information
after that information has been provided. Opting out must be done in writing. No
verbal requests can be accepted. Members who wish to be excluded from
certain activities should contact the Privacy Officer of the CAWQ.
Permission
By completing a CAWQ membership application form, you are consenting to the
collection and use of the information provided. If you have "opted out", this optout
clause pertains to information received by CAWQ.
Changes to the Privacy Policy
If CAWQ changes its Privacy Policy, the changes will be posted on our website
and integrated in the By-Laws.
For more information please contact the Privacy Officer or Secretary of CAWQ.
MEMBERS' LOGIN
Username:
Password:
Become a member | Forgot password
NEWS
Farokh Kakar seeks to join IWA Emerging Water Leaders steering committee Farokh Kakar, Chair of the IWA-YWPs-Canada, has decided to extend her contribution to the YWPs community globally by joining the IWA Emerging Water Leaders steering committee. She is running for (a) YWP Coordinator or (b) Co-chair.
The voting link is https://www.surveymonkey.co.uk/r/Z692BYT
The deadline for voting is July 15, 2020.
The 12th Western Canadian Symposium has been cancelled
R.D. Tyagi wins a 2018 IWA Project Innovation Award Dear Friends, Colleagues and CAWQ board members, I would like to share with you the excellent news of winning the 2018 IWA Project Innovation Awards for Category 'Breakthroughs in Research and Development' in the 'Silver' Category. I personally received this award on behalf of my research group and on behalf of INRS in the award ceremony organized by IWA during the IWA biennial conference in Tokyo, Japan. Thank you all for your good wishes and support.
R.D. Tyagi
The 9th International Water Association (IWA) Membrane Technology Conference & Exhibition for Water and Wastewater Treatment and Reuse June 23-27, 2019
Toulouse, France
Peter Vanrolleghem is awarded the 2015 WEF President Award Peter was honored at WEFTEC 2015, Chicago, for outstanding contributions to both his Member Association (Reseau Environnement) and and to helping Ed and WEF achieve high priority global partnership and young professional engagement goals.
OUR SPONSORS
Hoskin Scientific
Last Updated: 2014-08-18© 2020 Canadian Association on Water Quality
Home
FranÃ§ais
Search
Contact Us
